Ernst W. Caspari Papers 1932-1980 Mss.Ms.Coll.1
American Philosophical Society
Ernst W. Caspari Papers
1932-1980
Mss.Ms.Coll.1
American Philosophical Society
9.5 Linear feet ca 10,000 items
Ernst Wolfgang Caspari was an important contributor to behavior and developmental genetics, working primarily on the mealmoth Ephestia. Trained in Alfred Kuhn's laboratory at the University of Göttingen (1933-1935), Caspari was forced from his position by the Nazis in 1933, escaping to the United States five years later. As a professor of biology at Lafayette College, Wesleyan University, and the University of Rochester, Caspari continued his research on Ephestia, mouse genetics, and behavior genetics until his retirement in 1975. The Caspari Papers includes correspondence, papers, grant reports, and lectures relating to Caspari's genetic research dating primarily from the period after his departure from Germany. In addition to substantial material on behavior genetics and human evolution, the collection includes correspondence relating to Caspari's editorial work for Advances in Genetics, and his involvement with the American Institute of Biological Sciences, the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, Fifth Banff Conference on Theoretical Psychology, Genetics Society of America, International Conference on the Unity of Science, Social Science Research Council, Committee on Genetics and Behavior, and the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission.
Caspari, Ernst W.
Genetics Note
This collection contains materials which relate to the history of genetics.
Academic Press Correspondence (257 items) 1946-1980
Advances in Genetics Correspondence (612 items) 1944-1979
Ahuja, Mulk Raj Correspondence (38 items) 1975-1979
American Institute of Biological Sciences Correspondence (35 items) 1960-1968
American Society of Naturalists Correspondence (67 items) 1960-1964
Anders, Fritz Correspondence (51 items) 1974-1980
Braun, Joachim Werner Correspondence (92 items) 1950-1953
Caspari, Ernst Wilhelm Manuscripts (Approximately 100 folders) 1956-1979
Caspari, Ernst Wilhelm -- Source Book in the History of Science Correspondence (31 items) 1961-1980
Caspari, Ernst Wilhelm and Ravin, Arnold -- Genetic Organization, volume II Correspondence (132 items) 1968-1974
Champlin, Arthur Kingsley Correspondence (27 items) 1965-1979
Chatard, Patricia Correspondence (53 items) 1966-1969
Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Correspondence (86 items) 1959-1966
Cotter, William B. Correspondence (51 items) 1956-1977
Dalton, Clark Correspondence (59 items) 1948-1970
Demerec, Milislav Correspondence (80 items) 1940-1963
Dobzhansky, Theodosius Correspondence (36 items) 1961-1971
Dunn, Leslie Clarence Correspondence (71 items) 1939-1971
Egelhaaf, Albrecht Correspondence (112 items) 1957-1978
Ehrman, Lee Rothschild Correspondence (27 items) 1962-1975
Eicher, Eva Mae Correspondence (97 items) 1965-1979
Erlenmeyer-Kimling, L. Correspondence (28 items) 1962-1973
Firshein, William Correspondence (43 items) 1960-1972
Genetics Correspondence (65 items) 1963-1973
Genetics Society of America Records (126 items) 1964-1967
Goodrich, Hubert B. Correspondence (109 items) 1945-1954
Gottlieb, Frederick Jay Correspondence (46 items) 1962-1978
Grants (Atomic Energy Commission) Correspondence (71 items) 1961-1970
Grants (National Science Foundation) Correspondence (139 items) 1957-1971
Green, Melvin Martin Correspondence (41 items) 1948-1968
Hamburg, David A. Correspondence (30 items) 1960-1974
Henke, Karl F. W. Correspondence (20 items) 1935-1956
Imberski, Richard B. Correspondence (27 items) 1966-1979
International Congress of Genetics. Fourteenth Congress Correspondence (44 items) 1974-1978
Roscoe B. Jackson Memorial Laboratory Correspondence (37 items) 1961-1976
Kuhn, Alfred Correspondence (72 items) 1936-1948
Mayr, Ernst Correspondence (36 items) 1947-1970
Melchers, Georg Correspondence (15 items) 1969-1976
Milano, Ann and Madelyn Correspondence (77 items) 1960-1963
Miller, Harry C. Correspondence (23 items) 1970-1973
Muth, Friedrich Wilhelm Correspondence (95 items) 1961-1970
National Research Council. Committee on Basic Research in Education Correspondence (112 items) 1970-1973
Nawa, Saburo Correspondence (71 items) 1961-1967
New England Psychological Association Correspondence (24 items) 1964-1965
Paigen, Kenneth Correspondence (61 items) 1951-1974
Parker, Evelyn D. Correspondence (27 items) 1969-1974
Piepho, Hans Correspondence (13 items) 1960-1975
Pohley, Heinz-Joachim Correspondence (62 items) 1958-1968
Schwarz, Ernst Correspondence (174 items) 1932-1964
Seiger, Marvin B. Correspondence (76 items) 1965-1978
Snell, George D. Correspondence (60 items) 1941-1979
Social Science Research Council. Committee on Genetics and Behavior Correspondence (59 items) 1961-1980
Stadler, David R. Correspondence (36 items) 1971-1973
Stern, Curt Correspondence (57 items) 1946-1970
Teicher, Luz S. Correspondence (57 items) 1972-1978
University of Rochester. Department of Biology Correspondence (35 items) 1969-1979
Vankin, George Lawrence Correspondence (80 items) 1958-1978
Vishniac, Wolf V. Correspondence (25 items) 1965-1966
Wallace, Bruce Correspondence (22 items) 1955-1971
Watson, Geoffrey S. Correspondence (91 items) 1957-1977
Wesleyan University Correspondence (102 items) 1954-1970
Related Archival Materials note
The APS has a complete run of Advances in Genetics during the periods it was edited by Milislav Demerec and Ernst Caspari ( Call no.: 575.05 Ad9 v.1-29).
Additional correspondence of Caspari's is located in the papers of Milislav Demerec (B D394), L.C. Dunn (B D917), James B. Murphy (B M956), and Curt Stern (Ms. Coll. 5).
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Ernst W. Caspari, 1980.
Scope and Contents note
The Caspari Papers provide a relatively complete record of the research and professional commitments of the developmental and behavioral geneticist, Ernst W. Caspari, after his emigration to the United States in 1938. The 9.5 linear feet of correspondence, manuscripts of papers, lecture notes, and grant reports center on Caspari's research on the genetics of the mealmoth Ephestia and mice and his interests in behavior genetics and evolutionary biology.
The heart of the collection is a thorough run of professional correspondence relating to Caspari's research and his collaborations with Milislav Demerec, L. C. Dunn and others, as well as his correspondence as editor of the journal Genetics and Advances in Genetics. In addition to manuscripts of several of Caspari's papers, the collection includes notes for lectures on developmental genetics, and a small number of grant reports for his research on Ephestia and on mice, and information on his service on the preparatory committees for the 10th and 14th International Congresses of Genetics.
The collection is organized in a single series, arranged alphabetically by the name of the correspondent, writer, or subject. There are approximately 20 photomicrographs.
Biographical/Historical note
As a doctoral student and assistant professor at the University of Göttingen, Ernst Caspari was part of Alfred Kuhn's research team investigating the developmental genetics of the mealmoth Ephestia kuhniella. In his groundbreaking work on the effects of a pleiotropic gene, Caspari helped establish the basis for sorting out the complex relationship between genes and the temporal and spatial sequence of events in ontogeny, and he contributed to Kuhn's "one gene, one enzyme" hypothesis. With the rise to power of the Nazi Party, however, Caspari's career in Germany came to an abrupt end and in 1933 he was forced to leave the country. After three years as an assistant in microbiology at the University of Istanbul, where his research was restricted to disease transmission by mosquitoes and bedbugs, he arrived in the United States in 1938 to take up a fellowship at Lafayette College, later earning an appointment as assistant professor of biology.
At Lafayette, Caspari developed fruitful collaborations with L. C. Dunn of Columbia University and his graduate student Paul R. David, working on a variety of problems in mouse genetics, and after studying the effects of the kinky tail mutant, he developed what would become a lifelong interest in behavior genetics. He also managed to revive his work with Ephestia, exploring biochemical aspects of the aa eye color mutant. He remained active in both systems, Ephestia and the mouse, for the remainder of his career.
After becoming a naturalized citizen in 1944, Caspari moved to the University of Rochester to work with another German refugee, Curt Stern, on projects associated with the genetics program of the Manhattan Project. The Rochester group was commissioned to investigate the influence of chronic irradiation by low doses of gamma rays on the mutation rates of genes in the fruitfly Drosophila.
Upon moving to Wesleyan University in 1946, Caspari returned to his interests in the developmental genetics of Ephestia, including pleiotropy (especially behavioral effects), cytoplasmic inheritance, gene modifiers, and evolutionary effects such as selective differentials. During a two-year leave of absence at the Department of Genetics at Cold Spring Harbor (1947-1949), he collaborated with several colleagues to determine the protein differences between the wildtype a+a+ genotype and the aa mutant genotype of Ephestia (as well as another moth Ptychopoda seriata), and he investigated antibody formation in caterpillars and mitochondrial differences in genetic strains of mice. He was twice a fellow of the Center for Advanced Studies in the Behavioral Sciences at Stanford University (1956-1957 and 1965-1966) working in behavior genetics.
Although administrative commitments as department chair (1960-1966) somewhat curtailed Caspari's research after his return to Rochester in 1960, he and a visiting German colleague, H. J. Pohley, worked productively on somatic mutations induced by purine analogues and on interactions between the endocrine system and developing tissues in Ephestia, and he helped develop a refresher course on behavior genetics for the American Society of Zoologists in 1964. He retired to emeritus status at Rochester in 1975.
Throughout his career Caspari was active in professional organizations, serving as Vice President and President of the Genetics Society of America (1965 and 1966), and Vice President of the American Society of Naturalists (1960). He made a particular impact on the profession as an editor of both Advances in Genetics (1960-1970) and later of Genetics (1968-1972), and in service on the editorial boards of American Naturalist, Behavior Genetics, and Behavioral Science. He was elected to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences in 1959 and was recipient of the Theodosius Dobzhansky Award for Research by the Behavior Genetics Association in 1979.
Ahuja, M. R. (Mulkh Raj), 1933-; American Institute of Biological Sciences.; Anders, Fritz Wilhelm, 1919-; Banff Conference on Theoretical Psychology; Braun, J. Werner, (Joachim Werner), 1914-1972; Calhoun, John B.; Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (Stanford, CA).; Champlin, Arthur Kingsley, 1938-; Chatard, Patricia M.; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory.; Cotter, William Bryan, Jr., 1926-; Dalton, Howard Clark; Demerec, M., (Milislav), 1895-1966; Dobzhansky, Theodosius Grigorievich, 1900-1975; Egelhaaf, Albrecht, 1922-; Ehrman, Lee; Eicher, Eva M. (Eva Mae), 1939-; Erlenmeyer-Kimling, L.; Firshein, W. (William), 1930-; Gottlieb, Frederick Jay, 1935-; Green, Melvin M.; International Conference on the Unity of the Sciences; Kühn, Alfred, 1885-1968; Mayr, Ernst, 1904-2005; McClintock, Barbara, 1902-1992; Milano, Ann; Milano, Madelyn; Muth, Friedrich Wilhelm; Nawa, Saburo; Pohley, Heinz-Joachim; Schwarz, Ernst, 1989-; Smith, Woollcott; Social Science Research Council (U.S.). Committee on Genetics and Behavior.; Sonneborn, T.M., (Tracy Morton), 1905-1981; Stern, Curt, 1902-1981; Teicher, Luz S.; United States. Atomic Energy Commission; University of Rochester--Faculty; Vankin, George Lawrence, 1931-; Watson, Geoffrey, 1942-; Wesleyan University--Faculty; Williamson, D.L.; Ziegler, Irmgard; Advances in Genetics; Behavior genetics.; Developmental genetics; Ephestia; Genetics; Grant applications; Human evolution; Lectures; Lepidoptera--Research grants; Mouse--Genetics; Photographs; Political refugees--Germany
- Ernst W. Caspari Papers, 1932-1980; 9.5 lin. feet
  - Abeelen, J. H. F. van, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Abernethy, Virginia, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Academic Press, 1946-1980; 9 folders (257 items) (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Folder 1 (1946) only:
    Demerec, Milislav
    Jacoby, Kurt
    Editorial matters; Publication
  - Advances in Genetics, 1944-1979; 612 items (Box 1)
    Editorial matters; Genetics; Invitations; Publication
    - Abbott, Ursula K.
      Mc, Carrey, John R.
    - Abrahamson, John R. (Box 1)
    - Allard, R. W. (Box 1)
    - Baker, William K. (Box 1)
    - Barry, Edward G. (Box 1)
    - Boyes, J. Wally (Box 1)
    - Bradshaw, A. D. (Box 1)
    - Briles, W. Elwood (Box 1)
    - Brown, Spencer W. (Box 1)
    - Casselton, L. A. (Box 1)
    - Chu, Ernest H. Y. (Box 1)
    - Clausen, Jens (Box 1)
    - Cleland, Ralph E. (Box 1)
    - Courtright, James (Box 1)
    - Curtiss, Roy (Box 1)
    - Delbruck, Max (Box 1)
    - Demerec, Milislav (Box 1)
    - Dobzhansky, Theodosius (Box 1)
    - Dodds, K. S. (Box 1)
    - Doermann, A. H. (Box 1)
    - Dunn, L. C. (Box 1)
    - Eicher, Eva M. (Box 1)
    - Eisenstark, Abraham (Box 1)
    - Englesberg, Ellis (Box 1)
    - Ephrussi, Boris (Box 1)
    - Fox, Alan S. (Box 1)
    - Frankhauser, Gerhard (Box 1)
    - Gardner, Eldon J. (Box 1)
    - Goldberger, Robert (Box 1)
    - Green, Melvin M. (Box 1)
    - Gross, Paul R. (Box 1)
    - Hammerling, J. (Box 1)
    - Hart, Gary E. (Box 1)
    - Hartman, Philip E. (Box 1)
    - Hess and Meyer (Box 1)
      Hess, Oswald
      Meyer, Gunther F.
    - Hoch, James A. (Box 1)
    - Hutt, F. B. (Box 1)
    - Jacob, François (Box 1)
    - Jain, Subodh K. (Box 1)
    - Jenkins, Merle T. (Box 1)
    - Jones, Donald F. (Box 1)
    - Kafer-Boothroyd, Etta (Box 1)
    - Kaiser, Dale (Box 1)
    - King, R. C. (Box 1)
    - Kitzmiller, James B. (Box 1)
    - Konzak, D. F. (Box 1)
    - Lederberg, E. M. (Box 2)
    - Lush, I. E. (Box 2)
    - Lush, Jay L. (Box 2)
    - Malik, Vedpal S. (Box 2)
    - Maly, Roland (Box 2)
    - Martin, Albert (Box 2)
    - Maule, J. P. (Box 2)
    - Milkman, Roger (Box 2)
    - Mishra, N. C. (Box 2)
    - Mosig, Gisela (Box 2)
    - Muller, H. J. (Herman Joseph) (Box 2)
    - Nga, Been Hen (Box 1)
    - Oehlkers, F. (Box 2)
    - Organization of 1944, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Organization of, 1945, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Ouweneel, W. J. (Box 2)
    - Paigen, Kenneth (Box 2)
    - Parsons, P. A. (Box 2)
    - Patau, Klaus (Box 2)
    - Patterson, J. T. (Box 2)
    - Peacock, W. J. (Box 2)
    - Perkins, David (Box 2)
    - Poulson, Donald F. (Box 2)
    - Prescott, David M. (Box 2)
    - Ravin, Arnold (Box 2)
    - Rædei, G. P. (Box 2)
    - Reed, Sheldon C. (Box 2)
    - Rick, Charles M. (Box 2)
    - Righter, F. J. (Box 2)
    - Russell, Elizabeth S. (Box 2)
    - Sadgopal, Anil (Box 2)
    - Sager, Ruth (Box 2)
    - Schrader, Franz (Box 2)
    - Schwemmle, Julius (Box 2)
    - Sherman, Fred (Box 2)
    - Simmonds, N. W. (Box 2)
    - Smith, Harold H. (Box 2)
    - Sonneborn, Tracy M. (Box 2)
    - Staudt, Gunther (Box 2)
    - Stebbins, G. Ledyard (Box 2)
    - Steele, Dewey G. (Box 2)
    - Stern, Curt (Box 2)
    - Stinson, Harry (Box 2)
    - Stubbe, Hans (Box 2)
    - Suskind, Sigmund R. (Box 2)
    - Thoday, John M. (Box 2)
    - Unidentified (Box 2)
    - Ursprung, Heinrich (Box 2)
    - Westergaard, Mogens (Box 2)
    - Whiting, Anna R. (Box 2)
    - Wright, Theodore R. F. (Box 2)
    - Ziegler, Irmgard (Box 2)
  - Ahuja, Mulk Raj, 1975-1979; 2 folders (38 items) (Box 2)
    Biographical and personal data; Recommendations; Requests for aid in finding positions; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Aldine Publishing Co., 1974-1978 (Box 2)
  - Alexander, Richard D., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Altmann, Dagmar, 1978 (Box 2)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1962-1978 (Box 2)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1962 (Box 2)
  - American Educational Research Association, 1967 (Box 2)
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1960-1968; 2 folders (35 items) (Box 2)
    Lectures, public speaking -- Visiting lectures; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- American Institute of Biological Sciences; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - American Instrument Company, 1959 (Box 2)
  - American Psychological Association, 1960-1962 (Box 2)
  - American Society of Naturalists, 1960-1964; 2 folders (67 items) (Box 2)
    American Society of Naturalists -- Honorary membership; American Society of Naturalists -- Nominating committee; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - American Sociological Association, 1963; 3 folders (Box 2)
    Re: Caspari, "Interactions between Genetic Constitution and Social Factors in Man."
  - American Type Culture Collection, 1966 (Box 3)
    Bryson, Vernon
  - Anders, Fritz, 1974-1980; 3 folders (51 items) (Box 3)
    Biographical and personal data; Cancer, chemotherapy; Genetics; Honors; International Congress of Genetics; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; University of Giessen
  - Astaurov, B. L., 1963-1973 (Box 3)
    See also Genetics Society of America.
  - Austin, Gilbert R., 1967 (Box 3)
  - Bakheteyev, F. K., 1959-1963 (Box 3)
  - Banff Conference on Theoretical Biology, 5th, 1975-1980; 3 folders (Box 3)
    Royce, Joseph R.
  - Barnes, Jacqueline K., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Barr, H. J., 1973 (Box 3)
  - Beard, Raimon L., 1968 (Box 3)
  - Beckwith, William C. et al., 1964-1965 (Box 3)
    Re: "Determinants of Mental Illness."
  - Beensheim-Wiener, Marianne, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Behavior Genetics Association, 1979 (Box 3)
    Dobzhansky Award for research in behavior genetics.
  - Behavioral Science, 1963-1980; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Bell, Whitfield Jenks., 1974 (Box 3)
  - Belyaev, D. K., 1967-1975 (Box 3)
  - Benavides, Carlos Moreno, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - Benzer, Seymour, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Bernheimer, Alan W., 1959 (Box 3)
  - Bieber, Frederick R., 1975 (Box 3)
  - Biopsychology Symposium, 1978 (Box 3)
    "Development and Evolution of Brain Size: Behavioral Implications."
  - Blanc, A. D., 1959-1960 (Box 3)
  - Bodenstein, Dietrich, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Borstel R. C. von, 1961-1972 (Box 3)
  - Boyes, J. Wally, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Braun, Hugo, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Braun, Joachim Werner, 1950-1953; 3 folders (92 items) (Box 3)
    Bacterial genetics; Biographical and personal data; Research support -- U. S. Army Chemical Corps
  - Bregman, Allyn A., 1976 (Box 3)
  - Bresler, Jack B., 1971 (Box 3)
  - Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1963-1969 (Box 3)
  - Brosin, Henry W., 1964-1967 (Box 3)
  - Buchert, Janson G., 1959-1960 (Box 3)
  - Burla, Hans, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Burns, John M., 1968 (Box 3)
  - Calhoun, John B., 1976-1978; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Bernard G., 1968-1972 (Box 3)
    See Sexual Selection and the Descent of Man.
  - Cancro, Robert, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Caspari, Ernst W., 1956-1979; Approximately 100 folders
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Biographical and personal data; Cytogenetics; Evolution; Genetics -- Ephestia; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Mouse genetics; Population genetics; Radiation genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Behavior Genetics, 3 folders (Box 3)
      Re: "Perspectives in Behavior Genetics."
    - Bibliography and curriculum vitae (Box 3)
    - "Biological Basis of Female Hierarchies", 1975; 6 folders (Box 3)
    - "Biology and Evolution" (Box 3)
    - Commencement address for biology majors, 1979 (Box 3)
    - "Conceptual basis of biology" (Box 3)
    - "Cytoplasmic inheritance" (Box 4)
    - "Developmental genetics" (Box 4)
    - "Effects of radiation on populations" (Box 4)
    - "Evolution and behavior" (Box 4)
    - "Evolutionary outlook in human populations" (Box 4)
    - "Evolutionary theory and the evolution of the human brain", 3 folders (Box 4)
    - "The future of biology" (Box 4)
    - "Genetic analysis of the resting behavior in Xiphophorine fish" (Box 4)
    - "The genetic control of cytogenesis" (Box 4)
    - "Genetic changes induced by alpha-DNA" (Box 4)
    - "Genetic foundations of morphogenesis" (Box 4)
    - "Genetic implications of ethnology" (Box 4)
    - "Genetics of populations and its importance for human affairs" (Box 4)
    - "Goals and future of behavior genetics: a summation", 1978; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - "Heredity and environment in determination of behavior" (Box 4)
    - "Human origins", 1979 (Box 4)
    - "Interaction between biological and cultural evolution in man" (Box 4)
    - "Developmental genetics", 1972; 27 folders (Box 4-5)
      Note: Bio. 135
    - Lecture: The human species, 1971-1978; 15 folders (Box 5)
      Bio. 135
    - Lecture notes, 8 folders (Box 5-6)
    - The making of man (Box 6)
    - Miscellany (Box 6)
    - Mutations in mouse (Box 6)
    - "On the structure of genic material", 1956-1957 (Box 6)
    - "Organization of the cell" (Box 6)
    - Permission to reprint (Box 6)
    - Permit to import strains, 1958-1977; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - "Pigment formation in eye of Ephestia and its genetic determination" (Box 6)
    - "Present state of behavior genetics" (Box 6)
    - "Problems in behavior genetics" (Box 6)
    - Reviews, 1960-1966; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Security clearance (Box 6)
    - "Selective forces in evolution of man", 1961; 2 folders (Box 6)
      AAAS
    - "Transfer of genetic characters by allo-DNA in Ephestia", 2 folders (Box 6)
  - "Induction of somatic mutations by 5-bromodeoxyuridine in wing-scale system of Ephestia kuhniella Z.", 3 folders; Caspari, Ernst W. and Eicher (Box 6)
  - " Ephestia, Gottlieb, Frederick H. (Box 6)
    Gottlieb, Frederick J.
  - "The rise and fall of Lysenko", Caspari, Ernst W. and Marshak (Box 6)
  - "Developmental studies of the lethal gene Bld in the mouse", 2 folders; Vankin, G. Lawrence (Box 6)
    Vankin, G. Lawrence
  - "Influence of cytoplasmic pollen sterility on gene exchange between populations", 1965; Watson, G. S. (Box 6)
    Smith, Woollcott
    Watson, G. S.
  - "Xanthing dehydrogenase activity in eye color mutants of Ephestia", Wilcox, David R. (Box 6)
    Wilcox, David R.
  - Caspari, Fritz, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Catlin, Wesley, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Science (Stanford University), 1962-1977; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Champlin, Arthur K., 1965-1979; 2 folders (27 items) (Box 6)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Biographical and personal data; Graduate study; Mouse genetics
  - Chance, Michael R. A., 1959, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Chatard, Patricia M., 1966-1969; 4 folders (53 items) (Box 7)
    Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Biographical and personal data; Embryology, developmental genetics; Requests for aid in finding positions; University of Rochester
  - Chovnick, Arthur, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Clark, Kenneth E., 1966-1967, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Cleland, Ralph E., 1946 (Box 7)
  - Cochrane, Vincent W., 1966-1968 (Box 7)
  - Cobb, Susan, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Coelho, George V., 1968-1970 (Box 7)
  - Colbert, Phil, 1961-1965 (Box 7)
    Colbert, Edward
  - Cold Spring Harbor, "Past, present, and future" (Box 7)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory of Quantitative Biology, 1959-1966; 6 folders (86 items) (Box 7)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory -- Board of Directors; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder #1, 1959 (Box 7)
    - Folder #2, 1960 (Box 7)
    - Folder #3, 1961 (Box 7)
    - Folders #4-5, 1962; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Folder #6, 1963-1966 (Box 7)